Luke C Plummer

229 Vassar St.
Cambridge MA, 02139
413-835-1795 | lukulele@mit.edu

Profile

Luke is a master ukulele player, robotics designer, and audio engineer, whose creativity knows no bounds. He is passionate about his life and engineering endeavors, and enthusiastic about learning new skills and developing unique ways to integrate his many interests. Luke has background in mechanical design, music production and programming, but beyond his technical experience he is a well-developed writer and communicator.

Education

Massachusetts Institute of Technology September 2011-June 2014
Candidate for Bachelor of Science in Mechanical engineering with a concentration in audio systems engineering

Skills

- Design of small and large scale, mixed analog/digital audio systems for live performance and recording
- Music production from tracking to mastering and creative production
- Mechanical design of bicycles and sustainable bike technologies, small scale UAV aeronautics and robotics
- Media Software: Digital Performer, ProTools, Cubase, REAPER, Kontakt, Final Cut Pro, Unity
- Programming Languages: Java, Python, Objective C, JavaScript, Quick Basic, Max/MSP
- Software skills: Solidworks, XCode and COCOA Interface Builder, Microsoft Office

Experience

MIT Media Lab: Opera of the Future

January 2011 - Present

Undergraduate Researcher and Audio Systems Engineer

- Audio Software Engineer for Sleep No More, Opera of the Future's collaboration with Punchdrunk in NYC, spring 2012
- Software, hardware and sound design, and live sound engineering for internationally performed multi-media productions: Music | Machines, Spheres and Splinters, and the opera Death and the Powers

MIT Logarhythms

January 2011 - Present

Executive and Musical Producer

Member and studio manager of the MIT Logarhythms, all-male collegiate a cappella group. Manage production of studio albums from concept to tracking to mastering. Assistant producer of MIT Logarhythms' national award winning album *BAM*

MIT D-Lab: Cycle Ventures October 2011 - January 2012

Mechanical Project Engineer

Mechanical design and manufacturing projects with a team to develop low-cost rickshaw design improvements.

Projects including power measurement, 3D truss frame, and front suspension. Implementation of projects in Guwahati, India at the *Rickshaw Bank* factory, a project of the NGO *Center for Rural Development*.

Research with local builders and rickshaw drivers to evaluate effectiveness and ease of construction with new designs.